Berkeley, IL | 708-395-7006 | Jessica28100@yahoo.com

#### **Profile**

Marketing associate with digital marketing and social media experience, exceptional work ethic, and an *entrepreneurial spirit*. Always ready to assist teammates, learn, grow, and test new ideas. Experience in e-commerce, email marketing, and social media; some experience with digital marketing analytics and SEO/SEM.

### **Education**

**Certified Digital Marketing Professional Course,** Digital Marketing Institute, September 2019 (estimated date of completion)

HTML, CSS & Web Design Circuit Course: General Assembly, June 2019 (estimated date of completion)

Digital Marketing Course, General Assembly, 2017

Certificate in Social Media Management, Triton College, 2017

BS in General Business Administration, Northeastern Illinois University, 2004

■ 3.57/4.0 GPA | Graduated Cum Laude

### **Technical Skills**

- Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Outlook
- E-mail marketing: MailChimp and Emma
- E-commerce: Shopify Plus and Wordpress
- CRM software: SAP, Salesforce and Apprise
- Landing pages: LeadPages and Shogun (Shopify app)
- Advertising: Facebook Ads, Google Keyword Planner, Google AdWords and Google Analytics
- Project management: Asana
- Content design: Canva
- Communication: Skype for Business and Slack
- Asset submission/review: Connectpoint and LAGO
- Product/pricing maintenance: PIE, PIM, and GMP

# **Experience**

QUILL, Lincolnshire, IL

June 2018 - April 2019

## **Product Specialist**

- Received department recognition certificates: Working Together and Own It
- Coordinated with in-house agency to successfully launch all creative assets for the Viking Dura-ship Paper product launch
- Support Category Merchant in managing Paper and Mail and Ship product lines for online sales and margin
- Give direction to in-house agency on campaign assets and verify/approve creative
- Perform site checks to ensure customers have an effortless online experience
- Submit search result, SKU content, and family of product changes to optimize online customer shopping experience
- Utilize project management skills to coordinate the execution of projects that involve cross-departmental participation

## HONEY-CAN-DO INTERNATIONAL, Berkeley, IL

August 2017 - April 2018

### **Marketing Coordinator**

- Assisted in developing content ideas for monthly marketing calendar and launching a new B2C website on Shopify Plus
- Wrote initial copy for social media posts and e-mails, posted to social media, and launched e-mail campaigns
- Coordinated with graphic designer and photography team to obtain graphics, images, and other digital content
- Assisted in maintaining e-commerce website, manually entered new orders into CRM, and fulfilled orders in Shopify
- Headed up meetings for Ambiente and Housewares trade show planning and product selection
- Ran daily reports and analyzed sales data to select top performing products/categories for online promotion

### IGNITE USA, Chicago, IL

September 2015 - August 2017

### **Customer Account Specialist**

- Assisted in training co-workers during launch of department wide new CRM
- Managed daily open order reports, troubleshot order errors, root caused order issues, and managed customer inquiries
- · Communicated with Supply Chain, Purchasing, Marketing, and Warehouse teams to manage/plan for customer orders

## CANON USA, Itasca, IL

August 2011 - September 2015

### **Account Relations Representative II**

- Promoted to ARR II, created Service Authorization Exceptions form, and wrote several New Dealer quick reference quides
- Ran daily open order report, monitored and processed orders, and entered manual orders when necessary
- Lead quarterly marketing program review meetings and managed extranet set-up for Midwest Region's wholesale dealers
- Created and formatted Excel sales report summaries and created PowerPoint Dealer Review presentations for sales team